Herz, John H.; Papers ger015
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Research materials, 1944-1994; 10; 187 file folders
  - International Law: Merchant Vessels, 1950-1965; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 16)
  - International Law: Neutrality (Neutral Rights & Duties), 1939-1992; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 17)
  - International Law: Peace Settlement, 1944-1973; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 18)
  - International Law: Recognition, Non-Recognition, 1941-1993; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 19)
  - International Law: State Succession, 1939-1992; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 20)
  - International Law: Statehood, New States, 1941-1992; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 21)
  - International Law: Territorial Waters, 1948-1989; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 22)
  - International Law: Terrorism, 1972-1993; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 23)
  - International Law: Treaties, 1945-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 24)
  - International Law: Treatment of Aliens, 1939-1993; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 25)
  - International Law: War Crimes, 1941-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 26)
  - International Politics, 1956-1981; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 27)
  - International Rivers and Canals, 1949-1992; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 28)
  - Iran, 1974-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 29)
  - Iran Conflict, Gulf War, 1990-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 30)
  - Ireland, 1968-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 31)
  - Israel & Arab States (including Iraq, Egypt), 1976-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 32)
  - Italy, 1943-1994; Clippings (Box 27 (10-Research materials), Folder 33)
  - Japan, 1942-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 1)
  - Korea (North & South), 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 2)
  - Korea, 1974-1975; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 3)
  - Latin American Countries, 1951-1985; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 4)
  - Latin American Countries, 1986-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 5)
  - League of Nations, 1946-1975; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 6)
  - Legitimacy, 1974-1978; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 7)
  - Mexico, 1941-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 8)
  - Middle East (especially Israel), 1939; 1946-1979; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 9)
  - Nationaldemokratische Partei Deutschlands (NPD). Notes, clippings, Undated (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 10)
  - NATO, 1949-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 11)
  - New World Order, 1990-1993; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 12)
  - Open Societies, 1986; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 13)
  - Organization of American States (OAS), 1945-1991; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 14)
  - Poland, 1945-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 15)
  - Population. Notes, clippings, 1970-1984 (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 16)
  - Portugal, 1948-1993; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 17)
  - Prisoners of War: Korea, 1948-1958; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 18)
  - Refugee Problems, 1945-1994; Clippings (Box 28 (10-Research materials), Folder 19)
  - Resources (Soil, Water, Minerals), 1949-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 1)
  - Rio Summit Conference, 1992; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 2)
  - Rumania, 1945-1993; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 3)
  - Russia, Ukraine, Belarus, etc, 1991-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 4)
  - Russian Revolution, 1991; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 5)
  - Saar, 1950-1957; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 6)
  - Scandinavian Countries (Sweden, Norway, Denmark, Finland), 1949-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 7)
  - Security Dilemma, 1984-2004; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 8)
  - South Africa, 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 9)
  - Southeast Asia (Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines), 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 10)
  - Soviet and Russian Foreign Affairs, 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 11)
  - Spain, 1944-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 12)
  - Spiegel-Verlag proceedings, 1966 (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 13)
  - Statements, quotations. Notes, clippings, Undated (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 14)
  - Survival research, 1986-2005; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 15)
  - Switzerland, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 16)
  - Terrorism, 1973-1981; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 17)
  - Turkey, 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 18)
  - United Nations: general, 1945-1994; Clippings (Box 29 (10-Research materials), Folder 19)
  - United Nations: Cases (General Assembly, Security Council), 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 1)
  - United Nations: ECOSOC, 1947-1975; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 2)
  - United Nations: Membership issues, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 3)
  - United Nations: Secretariat, 1951-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 4)
  - United Nations: Trusteeship affairs, 1946-1990; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 5)
  - United Nations: UNESCO, Cultural Cooperation, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 6)
  - U.S. Congress, Elections, 1949-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 7)
  - U.S. Crime & Punishment, 1970-1972; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 8)
  - U.S. Economy & Related Problems (e.g. health care), 1977-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 9)
  - U.S. Elections, Campaign Financing, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 10)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy, 1940-1980; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 11)
  - U.S. Foreign Policy, 1981-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 12)
  - U.S. Government, 1950-1962; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 13)
  - U.S. Intelligence, esp. CIA, 1975-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 14)
  - U.S. Labor Relations, Poverty, Welfare, etc., 1969-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 15)
  - U.S. Law, Courts, Justice, 1957-1994; Clippings (Box 30 (10-Research materials), Folder 16)
  - U.S. Media, Education, 1984-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 1)
  - U.S. Minorities, Race Relations, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 2)
  - U.S. Political Parties, 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 3)
  - U.S. Presidency, 1952-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 4)
  - U.S. Territories: Puerto Rico, etc., 1991-1992; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 5)
  - U.S.S.R.: Foreign Affairs, 1945-1991; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 6)
  - U.S.S.R.: Soviet Bloc, 1988-1993; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 7)
  - U.S.S.R.: Soviet Culture, Education, Purges, 1944-1993; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 8)
  - U.S.S.R.: Soviet Economy, Labor, 1946-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 9)
  - Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, 1949-1972; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 10)
  - Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, 1972-1979; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 11)
  - Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos, 1980-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 12)
  - Vietnam: War Crimes, 1963-1975; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 13)
  - WHO, International Red Cross, 1948-1993; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 14)
  - World Views, 1978-1980; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 15)
  - Yugoslavia (Croatia, Bosnia, Slovenia, Macedonia), 1948-1994; Clippings (Box 31 (10-Research materials), Folder 16)
  - Oversize materials, 10.188 (Box 31 (10-Research materials))
    - Diplomas, documents, 1928-1951 (Box 32 (10-Research materials), Folder 1)
    - Portrait photograph (11 x 16) of Jacob Wolfowitz, Undated (Box 32 (10-Research materials), Folder 2)
- Audio and video tapes, 11
  This series contains audio tapes of the Human Survival Symposium organized by Herz in 1988 at C.U.N.Y., audio tapes of the 1998 reception given in Herz's honor, and a copy of the video From Swastika to Jim Crow (1999), in which Herz and other scholars who taught at black colleges are featured.
  - Audio tapes on the Symposium on Human Survival under the direction of John Herz. CUNY Graduate Center, 1988 March 28; 3 (Box 33 (11-Audio and video tapes))
  - Audio tapes of Herz Speech & Reception at CUNY, 1998 September 15; 3 (Box 33 (11-Audio and video tapes))
  - Video tape:From Swastika to Jim Crow. Pacific Street Films, 1999 (Box 33 (11-Audio and video tapes))